[kooky music]
[古怪的音乐]
*
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
[alarm rings]
[警报响起]
[ringing stops]
[铃声停止]
- IT'S QUITTING TIME,
SPONGEBOB.
- 下班时间到了，
海绵宝宝。
GO HOME.
回家吧。
- HMM.
- 唔。
- QUIT-TING TIME!
- 戒烟时间到了！
- [sniffs]
- [嗅嗅]
- GO HOME!
- 回家吧！
[watch beeps]
[注意蜂鸣声]
- OH, MY.
IT'S TIME TO GO HOME.
- 哦，我的。
是时候回家了。
SQUIDWARD,
WHAT ARE YOU STILL DOING HERE?
章鱼哥，
你还在这里做什么？
- [frustrated scream]
- [沮丧的尖叫声]
- WHAT AM I GOING TO DO
WITH YOU?
- 我要做什么
和你在一起吗？
I CAN'T THROW YOU AWAY.
我不能把你扔掉。
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
[horn honks]
[喇叭鸣响]
BLEH!
哎呀！
[flies buzzing]
[苍蝇嗡嗡声]
BUT I DO HAVE TO THROW AWAY
THE TRASH.
但我必须扔掉
垃圾。
[loud breathing]
[大声呼吸]
WHAT'S THIS?
这是什么？
SOMEONE THREW AWAY A BOOK.
有人扔掉了一本书。
YOU SHOULDN'T
THROW AWAY BOOKS.
你不应该
扔掉书籍。
- [growling]
- [咆哮]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
- [teeth chattering]
- [牙齿打颤]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
OH, SANDY?
YOU'RE A TRASH MONSTER?
哦，桑迪？
你是垃圾怪物吗？
- HECK, NO.
- 哎呀，不。
I WAS BREAKING A RECORD
我打破了记录
FOR ROOTING AROUND
IN A TRASH BIN.
为了扎根周围
在垃圾桶里。
IT'S ALL RIGHT HERE
一切都在这里
IN THE GUINNESS O'RIPLEY
ENORMOUS BOOK
在吉尼斯奥里普利
大书
OF CURIOSITIES, ODDITIES,
AND WORLD RECORDS.
好奇心、怪事、
和世界纪录。
LOOKEE HERE, SPONGEBOB.
看这里，海绵宝宝。
"STARING RECORD: FIVE DAYS."
“凝视记录：五天。”
"MOST FRIES UP NOSE,
“大多数炸鼻子，
HOLDING YOUR BREATH."
屏住呼吸。”
- WOW.
- YES, SIREE.
- 哇。
- 是的，西莉。
I SWEAR
BY THE POWER OF TEXAS,
我发誓
凭借德克萨斯州的力量，
I'M GOING TO BREAK ALL
THE RECORDS IN THIS HERE BOOK!
我要打破一切
这本书里的记录！
WHAT'S THE NEXT CHALLENGE?
下一个挑战是什么？
- LET ME SEE.
OOH.
- 让我看看。
哦。
"WORLD'S LONGEST TONGUE."
“世界上最长的舌头。”
- WELL, THAT'S EASY.
- 嗯，这很简单。
[stretching sounds]
[伸展声]
106, 107...
106、107...
106、107……
- HOLD TIGHT, SANDY.
[grunts]
- 坚持住，桑迪。
[咕哝]
- 108, 109, 110.
- 108、109、110。
- THAT'S IT, SANDY.
YOU DID IT.
- 就是这样，桑迪。
你做到了。
- YEEHAW!
- 耶哈！
[thud]
[砰]
- LET'S SEE--YIKES!
- 让我们看看——哎呀！
SWEET MOTHER OF PEARL.
甜美的珍珠母贝。
- IS IT DANGEROUS?
- 危险吗？
- YEAH, YOU COULD SAY THAT.
- 是的，你可以这么说。
YOU HAVE TO EAT AS MUCH CHUM
AS YOU CAN.
你必须吃尽可能多的密友
尽你所能。
- CHUM, HUH?
THAT'S NOT TOO BAD.
- 密友，嗯？
这还不错。
- RAW.
- 生的。
- RAW?
[gulps]
- 生的？
[吞咽]
- YOU WANT WHAT?
- 你想要什么？
- ONE ORDER OF CHUM PLEASE.
- RAW.
- 请点一份密友。
- 生的。
- LOOK, I KNOW I'M AN EVIL,
HEARTLESS MASTERMIND,
- 看，我知道我是一个邪恶的人，
无情的主谋，
BUT NO ONE CAN INGEST RAW CHUM
AND SURVIVE.
但没有人可以摄入生鱼片
并生存下来。
- OH, YEAH?
- 哦，是吗？
WELL, CHARLIE MACKEREL,
THE CURRENT RECORD HOLDER DID.
嗯，查理鲭鱼，
当前的记录保持者做到了。
- REALLY?
- 真的吗？
- FOR 30 SECONDS.
- 30 秒。
- WELL, IT'S YOUR FUNERAL.
- 好吧，这是你的葬礼。
[wheels squeaking]
[车轮吱吱作响]
- OKAY, SANDY.
EAT UP.
- 好吧，桑迪。
吃吧。
[chum wheezes]
[喘息声]
- UH, SPONGEBOB,
I'VE CHANGED MY--
- 呃，海绵宝宝，
我改变了我的——
[groans]
[呻吟]
[gulps]
[吞咽]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[monstrous grunting]
[可怕的咕噜声]
WORLD! RECORD!
世界！记录！
[beeping]
[嘟嘟声]
- SANDY, YOU DID IT.
YOU SURVIVED.
- 桑迪，你做到了。
你活了下来。
- AH!
- 啊！
- UH-OH.
HOLD ON, SANDY.
- 呃-哦。
坚持住，桑迪。
I KNOW JUST WHAT YOU NEED.
我知道您需要什么。
[inhales]
[吸气]
A KRABBY PATTY.
蟹肉饼。
[bell dings]
[铃声]
[rooster crows]
- [coughs, gasps]
[公鸡打鸣]
- [咳嗽、喘气]
I DID IT!
I'M ALIVE.
我做到了！
我还活着。
I CAN'T WAIT
TO SHOW THEM EXPERTS
我等不及了
向他们展示专家
THE PICTURES
OF MY RECORD-BREAKING FEATS.
图片
我的破纪录壮举。
- OH, NO.
I FORGOT MY CAMERA.
- 哦，不。
我忘记带相机了。
- WHAT?
SPONGEBOB!
- 什么？
海绵宝宝！
I NEED PHOTOGRAPHIC PROOF
OF MY AMAZING DEEDS.
我需要照片证明
我的惊人事迹。
- I'LL GO GET THE CAMERA.
- 我去拿相机。
- WELL, HURRY UP.
I'VE GOT RECORD-BREAKING TO DO.
- 好吧，快点。
我有打破纪录的任务要做。
- OH, MY.
- 哦，我的。
[robots beeping]
[机器人发出嘟嘟声]
- GOT YOUR CAMERA?
- 你带相机了吗？
- YOU BETCHA.
- 你猜对了。
- GREAT.
- 伟大的。
TAKE A PICTURE OF ME CHUCKING
THIS LAST WOODCHUCK
给我拍一张吃东西的照片
最后一只土拨鼠
TO BREAK THE WOODCHUCK CHUCKING
WORLD RECORD.
打破土拨鼠的咀嚼
世界纪录。
READY, COUSIN EARL?
准备好了吗，厄尔表弟？
- LET HER RIP, DARLIN'!
- 让她撕裂吧，亲爱的！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- [robotic voice]
100 WOODCHUCKS CHUCKED.
- [机器人声音]
100 只土拨鼠被夹住。
RECORD BROKEN.
记录被打破。
- THANKS FOR ALL YOUR HELP,
COUSINS.
- 感谢您的帮助，
表兄弟。
[chattering]
[喋喋不休]
- ANYTIME.
- SEE YOU ALL NEXT CHRISTMAS.
- 随时。
- 下个圣诞节见。
BYE.
再见。
- WOW, SANDY.
WHAT IS ALL THIS?
- 哇，桑迪。
这是什么？
- I'VE DECIDED TO GO ABOUT
THIS SCIENTIFICALLY.
- 我决定去
这是科学的。
I FEEL WITH CAREFUL PLANNING
AND PRECISE DELEGATION
我觉得需要仔细计划
精准授权
OF APPROPRIATE TASKS,
适当的任务，
I CAN MANAGE
THE SUCCESSFUL COMPLETION
我能应付
圆满完成
OF THE MAXIMUM NUMBER
OF RECORDS BROKEN
最大数量的
打破记录的数量
IN THE LEAST AMOUNT OF TIME.
在最短的时间内。
BOOK.
书。
PICTURE.
图片。
- HERE YOU GO.
- 干得好。
- THANK YOU.
- 谢谢。
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
SO WHAT'S NEXT?
那么下一步是什么？
OH, YEAH.
"LONGEST TOOTH."
哦，是的。
“最长的牙齿。”
HOW'S THE CALCIUM INFUSION
GOING?
钙输液怎么样
去吗？
IT IS READY, MS. CHEEKS.
准备好了，女士。脸颊。
- OUTSTANDING.
- 杰出的。
HERE. HOLD THIS.
这里。按住这个。
[squirts]
[喷]
[groans]
[呻吟]
[thud]
[砰]
HOW DID I DO?
我做得怎么样？
- PLEASE HOLD THIS END.
- 请握住这一端。
35 FEET.
35 英尺。
RECORD BROKEN.
记录被打破。
[thud]
[砰]
- OUCH.
- 哎呀。
[thud]
[砰]
- TAKE A PICTURE.
- 拍张照片。
- SAY, "CHEESE."
- 说，“奶酪。”
- CHEESE.
- 奶酪。
[camera shutter clicks]
[相机快门声]
PICTURE.
- HERE YOU GO.
图片。
- 干得好。
- THANK YOU.
- 谢谢。
NEXT,
"SPICIEST CHILI GARGLE."
接下来，
“最辣的辣椒漱口水。”
[chili bubbling]
[辣椒冒泡]
[gulping]
[吞咽]
[gargling]
[漱口]
[gulps]
- GOT IT.
[吞咽]
- 明白了。
YOU OKAY?
你还好吗？
[stomach rumbling]
[肚子咕咕叫]
[shouts]
[喊叫]
- [sniffs]
- [嗅嗅]
DO YOU SMELL SOUP?
你闻到汤味了吗？
- WHAT'S NEXT?
- 下一步是什么？
- "LARGEST RUBBER BAND BALL."
- “最大的橡皮筋球。”
[camera shutter clicks]
[相机快门声]
[rubber band snaps]
[橡皮筋按扣]
- WHOO-HOO!
WHAT'S NEXT?
- 呼呼！
接下来是什么？
- "MOST COBRAS MILKED."
- “大多数眼镜蛇都挤奶。”
- [giggles]
SAY, "CHEESE."
- [咯咯笑]
说：“奶酪。”
- CHEESE.
- 奶酪。
- [gasps]
NICE SNAKES.
- [喘气]
不错的蛇。
[choking]
[窒息]
- NEXT?
- 下一个？
- "MOST WALNUTS IN MOUTH."
- “嘴里最多的核桃。”
- JUST ONE MORE.
- 再多一个。
OH, NO.
哦，不。
[shouts]
[喊叫]
NEXT!
下一个！
- "MOST CHAIN SAWS JUGGLED."
- “大多数链锯都是杂耍的。”
[chain saws buzzing]
[电锯嗡嗡作响]
- OKAY, SHOOT.
- 好吧，开枪。
- GOT IT.
SO, UH, HOW DO YOU STOP?
- 知道了。
那么，呃，你怎么停下来？
- WHAT?
- I SAID, "HOW DO YOU STOP?"
- 什么？
- 我说，“你怎么停下来？”
- WHAT?
- HOW DO YOU STOP?
- 什么？
- 你怎么停下来？
- WHY, THAT'S EASY.
I JUST...
- 为什么，这很简单。
我只是...
[grunts]
STOP.
[咕哝]
停止。
THEN RUN LIKE HECK.
然后狂奔。
NOT THAT WAY.
不是那样的。
COME ON, SPONGEBOB.
PULL YOURSELF TOGETHER.
来吧，海绵宝宝。
振作起来。
WE'VE STILL GOT
A TON OF RECORDS TO BREAK.
我们还有
大量记录有待打破。
OH, YEAH.
YOU'RE GOING TO LOVE THIS ONE.
哦，是的。
您一定会喜欢这个。
- I DON'T KNOW, SANDY.
- 我不知道，桑迪。
THIS IS GETTING
KIND OF DANGEROUS.
这正在得到
有点危险。
- COME ON,
YOU DON'T NEED YOUR HELMET.
- 来吧，
您不需要头盔。
THIS ONE'S OUTSIDE.
FOLLOW ME.
这个在外面。
跟我来。
- OH, MY.
- THERE IT IS.
- 哦，我的。
- 就在那里。
THE WORLD'S LARGEST HOUSE
OF CARDS.
世界上最大的房子
卡片。
- THAT'S AMAZING.
- 太棒了。
GET IN FRONT
SO I CAN TAKE A PICTURE.
走在前面
这样我就可以拍照了。
- NAH. LET'S GET A SHOT
FROM THE TOP.
- 不。让我们来尝试一下
从顶部。
[elevator bell dings]
[电梯铃声]
- WHAT THE--?
- 什么--？
OH, HEY.
哦，嘿。
IT'S SOLITAIRE.
这是纸牌。
I LOVE THIS GAME!
[laughs]
我喜欢这个游戏！
[笑]
HEY, I KICK A TOUCHDOWN!
嘿，我触地得分！
[cards jingling]
[卡片叮当作响]
[both screaming]
[两人尖叫]
- WHAT'S NEXT?
- 下一步是什么？
- UM, I THINK I SMELL
GARY'S SANDBOX.
- 嗯，我想我闻到了
加里的沙盒。
GOT TO GO CLEAN IT.
必须去清理它。
NOW.
现在。
I THINK YOU BROKE A RECORD
TODAY, GARY.
我认为你打破了记录
今天，加里。
WORLD'S STINKIEST LITTER BOX.
EWW.
世界上最臭的垃圾箱。
EWW。
OOH.
哦。
I'M WORRIED ABOUT SANDY.
我很担心桑迪。
SHE'S GOT
RECORD-BREAKING FEVER.
她有
破纪录的狂热。
[Gary meows]
[加里喵喵声]
YOU'RE RIGHT.
SHE DOES NEED MY HELP.
你说得对。
她确实需要我的帮助。
I MUST STOP THIS MADNESS!
我必须阻止这种疯狂！
IT'S ALL THAT BOOK'S FAULT.
都是那本书的错。
THE BOOK IS EVIL.
这本书是邪恶的。
THE BOOK MUST BE DESTROYED!
这本书必须被毁掉！
[electricity crackles]
[电流爆裂声]
[robot beeping]
[机器人嘟嘟声]
[robotic voice]
WHY DON'T YOU TAKE FIVE?
[机器人声音]
你为什么不拿五个呢？
I WILL HOLD THE BOOK.
我会拿着这本书。
- THANK NEPTUNE'S GEARS.
- 感谢海王星的齿轮。
MY WHEELS ARE KILLING ME.
我的车轮快要死了。
- HEY! WHERE DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE GOING?
- 嘿！你认为在哪里
你要去吗？
GET BACK IN LINE.
重新排队。
I NEED EVERY AVAILABLE ROBOT
FOR THIS ONE.
我需要每一个可用的机器人
对于这个。
MOST ROBOTS BUILT
AND DESTROYED IN A DAY.
建造最多的机器人
一天之内就被摧毁了。
[crushing sounds]
[破碎的声音]
- 656.
- 656。
[crushing sounds]
657.
[破碎的声音]
OH, THE ARTIFICIAL HUMANITY.
哦，人造人类。
- OH,
NO, YOU DON'T.
- 哦，
不，你不。
WE'RE ALL IN THIS TOGETHER.
我们都在一起。
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
[bell dings]
[铃声]
- 679. RECORD BROKEN.
- [squealing]
- 679. 记录被打破。
- [尖叫声]
[bell dings]
[铃声]
OKAY. SHUT HER DOWN.
好的。让她闭嘴。
- OH, MY--
- WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
- 哦，我的--
- 你怎么了？
- MY STOMACH FEELS FUNNY.
- WELL, LET'S HAVE A LOOK.
- 我的胃感觉很奇怪。
- 好吧，让我们看看。
SPONGEBOB?
- OH, HI, SANDY.
海绵宝宝？
- 哦，嗨，桑迪。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- SPONGEBOB,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- 海绵宝宝，
你在做什么？
- I'M HERE TO SAVE YOU
FROM--FROM THIS BOOK.
- 我是来救你的
来自——来自这本书。
I'M GOING TO DESTROY IT
BEFORE SOMEONE GETS KILLED.
我要毁掉它
在有人被杀之前。
I DON'T WANT
TO LOSE YOU, SANDY.
我不想要
失去你，桑迪。
[crying]
I DON'T WANT TO LOSE YOU!
[哭泣]
我不想失去你！
- OH, DON'T BE SILLY, SPONGEBOB.
I'M DONE WITH THAT BOOK.
- 哦，别傻了，海绵宝宝。
我已经看完那本书了。
I BEAT EVERY RECORD IN HERE.
我打破了这里的每一项记录。
IN FACT, I'VE INVITED
THE AUTHOR TO VERIFY
事实上，我已经邀请了
作者要验证
MY EMINENCE.
陛下。
- THANK YOU.
HMM.
- 谢谢。
唔。
YES. OH, MY.
是的。哦，我的。
I SEE.
WELL, THEN.
我懂了。
好吧，那么。
I'M AFRAID YOU'VE BROKEN
NO RECORDS.
我担心你已经崩溃了
没有记录。
both: HUH?
- THIS BOOK IS 30 YEARS OLD.
两人：嗯？
- 这本书已经有 30 年历史了。
THESE RECORDS
WERE BROKEN AGES AGO.
这些记录
很久以前就已经破碎了。
YOU, HOWEVER, HAVE SET
A BRAND-NEW RECORD.
然而，你已经设定了
全新记录。
MOST INJURIES SUSTAINED
WHILE HELPING A FRIEND.
大多数人受伤
在帮助朋友的同时。
- GOOD FOR YOU, SPONGEBOB.
- 对你有好处，海绵宝宝。
[shatters]
[破碎]
- UM, HOORAY.
- 嗯，万岁。
- SAY, "CHEESE."
[camera shutter clicks]
- 说，“奶酪。”
[相机快门声]